[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c835", "question": "Which space shuttle is named for the ship on which Robert Scott first sailed to Antarctica?", "answer": "The Discovery", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe734f2eec85e375820b240", "question": "What prison held Rudolf Hess after World War II?", "answer": "Spandau Prison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f5", "question": "In what U.S. City was the Rag\u00fa brand of Italian-style sauces first produced?", "answer": "Rochester, New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae9552574a5ce6b56b8253", "question": "Which river carved the Grand Canyon?", "answer": "Colorado River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a369", "question": "What is the capital of Monaco?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeac", "question": "Who was the second president of the United States?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5aab2f3358d116dab4aecb47", "question": "What nationality is the racing driver Jean Alesi?", "answer": "French", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59524338736d4be723796b67", "question": "How many of the same item can you get in the term \"Bakers Dozen\"?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f0", "question": "HBO's TV show \"True Blood\" is based on a book series by whom?", "answer": "Charlene Harris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b7", "question": "What are categorized as the biological class \"aves\"?", "answer": "Birds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab2d", "question": "Suva is the capital of which Melanesian country?", "answer": "Fiji", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a7c", "question": "Who wrote the book \"The Power of Positive Thinking\"?", "answer": "Norman Vincent Peale", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e4a", "question": "What's the name of the little boy who discovers \"Where the Wild Things Are\"?", "answer": "Max", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f3", "question": "What do you have if you suffer from podobromhidrosis?", "answer": "Smelly feet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c42d", "question": "How many calves does the average giraffe mother give birth to each time?", "answer": "One", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015ec6afe83fe1f2a824c01", "question": "What does the final day of Passover celebrate?", "answer": "The arrival of the Israelites to the Red Sea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590679b5ff9c0647b50a8051", "question": "On January 1, 2016, which Canadian province became the first one to allow the testing of self-driving vehicles on public roads?", "answer": "Ontario", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefc56f6ce05a3942286f3e", "question": "What 19th century opera singer was known as the \"Swedish Nightingale\"?", "answer": "Jenny Lind", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d43", "question": "Which Claude Monet painting is attributed to giving the Impressionist Movement its name?", "answer": "Impression, Sunrise", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76e69eec85e375820b2dd", "question": "Which country is famously shaped like an elephant's head?", "answer": "Thailand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae5", "question": "Who played Ike Turner in the 1993 Tina Turner biopic \"What's Love Got To Do With It?\"", "answer": "Laurence Fishburne", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f276fe83fe1f2a824c19", "question": "Who was the first high priest of Israel?", "answer": "Aaron", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9cb", "question": "What kind of animal is a Lurcher?", "answer": "Dog", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c2", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering Radium and Polonium?", "answer": "Marie Curie", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad7", "question": "Hydrargyrum is an old name for which element on the periodic table?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b963", "question": "How many quires are there in a ream?", "answer": "20", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c99f", "question": "What phenomenon is caused by the gravitational attraction of the Earth's moon?", "answer": "Tides", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592201b0a4edfd43a087addb", "question": "What is the first name of the fictional character \"Miss Marple\"?", "answer": "Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a72", "question": "Who was the first American artist to have a painting on display in the Louvre?", "answer": "James Whistler", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7b6", "question": "What is the capital of Belgium?", "answer": "Brussels", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922a", "question": "What Welsh songstress has performed the themes for three different Bond movies?", "answer": "Shirley Bassey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b38", "question": "What game does the Queen of Hearts order Alice to play in Alice in Wonderland?", "answer": "Croquet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6018bc8dd96d05b23b281657", "question": "Which country was the first to legalize same-sex marriage?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b84d", "question": "What is the Hebrew word for peace, used as both a greeting and a farewell?", "answer": "Shalom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c12e", "question": "Boxer Jersey Joe Walcott was better known as who?", "answer": "Arnold Raymond Cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd9", "question": "What word is the actual title of the 1979 hit typically called \"The Pina Colada Song\"?", "answer": "Escape", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60173fcf44491cbd7c5a17b6", "question": "What is the name of the pagan festival that used to be held during the same period as Valentine's Day?", "answer": "Lupercalia was a festival dedicated to Faunus, the Roman god of agriculture. It was held the middle of February.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6990a20565ad31a57c73f", "question": "What legendary athlete lit the Olympic torch at the 1996 Atlanta Olympics?", "answer": "Mohammed Ali", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb7", "question": "In The Green Lantern comic book series, what is the color used to represent will power?", "answer": "Green", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c14e", "question": "Porphyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "The color purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae29", "question": "In which decade did Winston Churchill win the Nobel prize for literature?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc2f0aacee580c7f8fd1e4c", "question": "Who said, \"Tell me and I forget. Teach me and I remember. Involve me and I learn.\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c7", "question": "What nickname was given to the brutal Royal Irish Constabulary Reserve Force in 1920?", "answer": "Black and Tans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bfd", "question": "Who wrote \"A Farewell to Arms\"?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af51", "question": "The Maginot line was a defensive system constructed to protect what?", "answer": "The French Border", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b04e", "question": "Which U.S. President signed the National Aeronautics and Space Act establishing NASA?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb0", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1980 comedy film \"Private Benjamin\"?", "answer": "Goldie Hawn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab6d", "question": "What year did Bangladesh declare its independence from Pakistan?", "answer": "1971", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600242964be4723ccac22189", "question": "Which novel was first published in October 1847 under the pen name \"Currer Bell\"?", "answer": "\"Jane Eyre\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4e35c06d333868d34d72c", "question": "Which empire did Charlemagne rule?", "answer": "The Holy Roman Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58bb3229e368446ca7bd6841", "question": "Which chemical element has the highest boiling point?", "answer": "Tungsten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a25ee9e6682715b82711cce", "question": "Which European republic was the first to reach Australia in 1606?", "answer": "The Dutch", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ece", "question": "What sitcom was almost titled \"Six of One\" or \"Across the Hall\"?", "answer": "Friends", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f98", "question": "In the traditional song, what did the children dance around \"on a cold and frosty morning\"?", "answer": "The mulberry bush", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de8", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"typhoon\"?", "answer": "Cantonese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdef", "question": "What's the alcohol in an Old Fashioned cocktail?", "answer": "Whiskey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a24d", "question": "What year did Huey Lewis and the News record the song \"Jacob's Ladder\"?", "answer": "1986", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339770", "question": "What movie features the four high school friends Jim, Finch, Oz and Kevin?", "answer": "American Pie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69b9820565ad31a57c761", "question": "Jimmy Carter served in which military branch?", "answer": "U.S. Navy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a493", "question": "Where in Australia did Captain Cook land?", "answer": "Botany Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8dd", "question": "What was Jesse Ventura's wrestling nickname?", "answer": "Jesse \"The Body\" Ventura", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe77075eec85e375820b2f9", "question": "Where is the \"Top of Europe\"?", "answer": "Jungfraujoch, Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c697", "question": "In the human body, what is produced by the Islets of Langerhans?", "answer": "Insulin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c64ffbde8045e48466b5", "question": "The asteroid that killed the dinosaurs is believed to have landed where?", "answer": "About 65 million years ago, an asteroid about 6 miles wide crashed into the Gulf of Mexico, killing 70% of all species on Earth.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c8a60190aac110e4167078", "question": "What year did the Boston Tea Party take place?", "answer": "1773", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba8", "question": "What is the name of the Princess Mario & Luigi have to rescue in the Super Mario Brothers Nintendo games?", "answer": "Princess Toadstool/Peach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b050", "question": "Whose assassination brought Hosni Mubarak to power in Egypt?", "answer": "Anwar Sadat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e44", "question": "What two-word phrase is the first writing to appear in \"Charlotte's Web\"?", "answer": "Some pig", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f5", "question": "In the movie \"Monty Python and the Holy Grail\", who lost both arms and both legs in a sword fight?", "answer": "The Black Knight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b8", "question": "What Miss America Pageant winner turned in her tiara on July 23, 1984?", "answer": "Vanessa Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98e", "question": "In what year did England win its first FIFA World Cup?", "answer": "1966", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f3", "question": "Cushat, Rock and Stock all types of which creature?", "answer": "Doves", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3a", "question": "Thomas Jefferson is depicted on what US coin?", "answer": "5 cent coin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e16", "question": "At the end of \"The Da Vinci Code\", the Holy Grail is revealed to be buried at what popular spot?", "answer": "The Louvre Museum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7a", "question": "What country's space travellers have been called \"taikonauts\" since 1998?", "answer": "China's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cdafce347d002c297e4da", "question": "What was Yehudi Menuhin's main profession?", "answer": "Violinist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a98c20565ad31a57c806", "question": "During World War II, what was the USS Indianapolis' secret mission?", "answer": "Delivering parts for the atomic bomb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc776ec223966ae8f888d", "question": "In TV, what is Leonard Hofstader's middle name?", "answer": "Leakey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ccf", "question": "In which Hitchcock movie is the protagonist confined to a wheelchair?", "answer": "Rear Window", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75e", "question": "What organ gave us the word \"hysterical\"?", "answer": "The uterus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0e562fcbed638185eaa2e", "question": "Where can you take part in the \"Battle of the Oranges\"?", "answer": "Ivrea, Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f3", "question": "Where is the Sea of Tranquility?", "answer": "The Moon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd9", "question": "Lansing is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c67", "question": "What Stephen King novel features the characters Annie Wilkes and Paul Sheldon?", "answer": "Misery", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59524639736d4be723796b6f", "question": "What infamous TV show is the saying \"Jumping the Shark\" based on?", "answer": "Happy Days", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed6", "question": "The Titanic picked up passengers in which\u00a0two\u00a0ports other than Southampton?", "answer": "Cherbourg and Queenstown", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff14008b0ee8c595b6d3993", "question": "Artist Andy Warhol suffered from what mental health condition?", "answer": "Hypochondria", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a829", "question": "What is the only New England state with no Atlantic coastline?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd96f2d23c87fd04dd15e40", "question": "What year did the Times Square Ball Drop first take place?", "answer": "1907, welcoming 1908", "category": "history"}, {"id": "591c37dc815febcc896f9275", "question": "What is the fourth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Cancer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339666", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Springfield's newspaper?", "answer": "The Springfield Shopper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beaf", "question": "How many hole cards is each player dealt in Texas Hold 'Em?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e806f6de59ea584496feb5", "question": "Which two South American countries do not share a land boundary with Brazil?", "answer": "Chile and Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60172d4c44491cbd7c5a177f", "question": "What general commanded the American Expeditionary Forces on the Western Front during World War I?", "answer": "John Joseph \"Black Jack\" Pershing GCB", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133893e", "question": "What armless statue in the Louvre is described as \"the most famous work of art of the ancient Greek sculpture\"?", "answer": "Venus de Milo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7ca1ff048f679a45abf8", "question": "What do you call a group of giraffes?", "answer": "A tower", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76673eec85e375820b280", "question": "Which two Great Lakes are connected by the Straits of Mackinac?", "answer": "Michigan and Huron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af25d77b63e5727cf5a4865", "question": "Vanilla Ice's song, \"Ice Ice Baby\" samples the bassline from which song?", "answer": "\"Under Pressure\" by Queen and David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16690f7c52aae91cc07af", "question": "What is New Year's Eve called in Scotland?", "answer": "Hogmanay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab136ebaab681b0929216d", "question": "Which car was the subject of the 2015 documentary, \u201cA Faster Horse\u201d?", "answer": "Ford Mustang", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a217", "question": "Who was the first winner of the British version of the TV reality show \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Craig Phillips", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5db03d96aa1c9af2684d79a3", "question": "In what year was \"Flag Day\" established as a national holiday in the US?", "answer": "\"Flag Day\" is not an official federal holiday but it is at the discretion of the President", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e94", "question": "What Harry Potter snacks come in flavors including earwax, booger, and vomit?", "answer": "Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339399", "question": "How many brothers did Ryan lose in the movie \"Saving Private Ryan\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a4d", "question": "Natty Bumppo was the creation of which author?", "answer": "James Fenimore Cooper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3b57c73aa70ea0b70ae8", "question": "Where was the first European settlement in Australia located?", "answer": "Port Jackson", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b57186167df192a942e335e", "question": "Which continent would you find the \"Strait of Magellan\" in?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a1e1d0eb5a031299b745737", "question": "Which painter, famous for his pop-art, died in 1997?", "answer": "Roy Lichtenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ab99cb521a8909e5c332d38", "question": "What country owns Corsica?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59db77bc0ab2c8f322317fee", "question": "Which holiday did Canada Day replace in 1982?", "answer": "Dominion Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d6", "question": "What city is located across the Columbia River from the city of Vancouver?", "answer": "Portland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5aab2f9058d116dab4aecb4b", "question": "What's the name of the technique for collecting measurements at a distance?", "answer": "Telemetry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b78f", "question": "What is the sum of all the numbers on a roulette wheel?", "answer": "666", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3dd044f0f6af5b066640", "question": "Andorra la Vella is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Andorra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "591c376d815febcc896f9270", "question": "What year did Dashiell Hammett publish the novel \"The Maltese Falcon\"?", "answer": "1929", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e9", "question": "What group's 1979 debut album was entitled \"Reproduction\"?", "answer": "Human League", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f4f", "question": "What rock group was behind the \"Mudshark Incident\" at Seattle's Edgewater Inn in 1969?", "answer": "Led Zeppelin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b49", "question": "Where did the Pied Piper play?", "answer": "Hamelin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a084", "question": "What was Disney's first film to win an Academy Award?", "answer": "Flowers and Trees", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b695", "question": "What color is the legendary Hope Diamond?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab1b20c4fda37788a9a1db6", "question": "Armagnac is a brandy originating from which area of France?", "answer": "Gascony", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5971e01d89261e916c8e09aa", "question": "Who are the actors that play Sam and Dean Winchester in the TV show \"Supernatural\"?", "answer": "Jared Padalecki and Jensen Ackles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989a8a3cb8751d53e7d75fc", "question": "Who won the fourth Super Bowl?", "answer": "Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59db78b50ab2c8f322317ff6", "question": "What was the name of Nazi Germany's secret police?", "answer": "Gestapo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad1", "question": "What is the nickname for Rome, Italy?", "answer": "Eternal City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339648", "question": "What was the nickname of Gene Hackman's character in The French Connection?", "answer": "Popeye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3dd", "question": "The name \"Pterodactyl\" is based on a Greek phrase meaning what?", "answer": "Wing finger", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d00", "question": "What letter accounts for one of every eight used in written English?", "answer": "E", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c6", "question": "What five-letter word did Time magazine coin in 1926 to refer to left-leaners?", "answer": "Pinko", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd1e", "question": "What computer language uses as its logo a blue mug with red steam rising from it?", "answer": "Java", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f167f2f7c52aae91cc07c0", "question": "What is a brickfielder?", "answer": "Hot and dry Southern Australian wind", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce5", "question": "What is Mr. Belvedere's given name?", "answer": "Lynn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b20", "question": "What is the name of the sarcastic housekeeper on \"Two and a Half Men\"?", "answer": "Berta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb9", "question": "Who are Nathan Wind, Vic Colfari, and Sir Stewart Wallace?", "answer": "Characters in the Beastie Boys music video \"Sabotage\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5904a3dfcf93664eb10486c0", "question": "Not including spin-offs or tie-ins, how many issues were released as part of the original \"Strangers in Paradise\" series that ended in 2007?", "answer": "90", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008c7ecf842fa4c4ba969f", "question": "In which novel would you find reference to the \"Cracks of Doom\"?", "answer": "The Lord of the Rings", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc98", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Catenaccio\"?", "answer": "Soccer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c42f", "question": "What is the longest and heaviest bone in the human body?", "answer": "Femur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a179", "question": "Which actor was \"The Postman\"?", "answer": "Kevin Costner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96ae623c87fd04dd15e16", "question": "Jeans are named for what European city?", "answer": "Genoa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c9e", "question": "What Ray Charles song was the basis for Kanye West's \"Gold Digger\"?", "answer": "I Got a Woman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b028", "question": "The major battle of what city was fought on January 8, 1815?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4dc", "question": "What fruit comes in Muscat and Scuppernong variety?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8d0", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the river Nile?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad6b", "question": "Who established a Vietnam memorial while consulting on the film \"The Deer Hunter\"?", "answer": "Jan Scruggs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd56", "question": "The Peabody Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Radio and television", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59029db7cad1ec93f27df751", "question": "What popular French apple brandy is made by distilling cider made from selected apples?", "answer": "Calvados", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339228", "question": "What is \"Shawshank\" in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "A prison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b07c", "question": "What WWII general was known as \"Old Blood and Guts\"?", "answer": "Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c19d", "question": "What former country was tennis player Martina Hingis born in?", "answer": "Czechoslovakia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7b", "question": "Who became prime minister of Cuba in 1959?", "answer": "Fidel Castro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c476", "question": "What type of animal was the first ever to be cloned from an adult cell?", "answer": "A sheep", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee6", "question": "What hit sitcom was based on the 1964 Tony Randall film \"The Brass Bottle\"?", "answer": "I Dream of Jeannie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133964c", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1943 movie \"My Friend Fllicka\"?", "answer": "Horse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea47c3ff048f679a45abad", "question": "What strangely named type of mackerel is also known as an Ono in Hawaii?", "answer": "Wahoo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a711", "question": "The city of Santa Cruz is located on the shores of what bay?", "answer": "Monterey Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecca05ec223966ae8f8897", "question": "What is the name of the alien race who were the adoptive parents of Samus in the \"Metroid\" franchise?", "answer": "The Chozo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57b", "question": "US city Milwaukee is located on the shores of what lake?", "answer": "Lake Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8b94ec223966ae8f8840", "question": "\"Mi Reflejo\" was a Spanish-speaking album released by which famous musician?", "answer": "Christina Aguilera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdb35ec223966ae8f88f1", "question": "In \"Raiders of the Lost Ark,\" what chases Indy out of the Temple of the Chachapoyan Warriors?", "answer": "A giant rolling boulder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b682", "question": "Which company took over production of Rolls-Royce cars in 2003?", "answer": "BMW", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339337", "question": "How many children did Lucy and Desi have?", "answer": "Two", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae92", "question": "Who changed her name to Rebecca Rolfe, after marrying John Rolfe?", "answer": "Pocahontas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe766b5eec85e375820b287", "question": "Captain Henry Morgan used what island as a base of buccaneer operations?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe51ece1bf59ab7d2e380e2", "question": "Who was responsible for the introduction of the Ford Mustang in 1964?", "answer": "Lee Iacocca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f0", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince\", who does Harry catch tentacula leaves?", "answer": "Professor Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600b87f21d8c1817608d53ec", "question": "What was the name of British Prince Philip's mother?", "answer": "Princess Alice of Battenberg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4ba949076251badbeac6", "question": "The first North American\u00a0English seasonal camp was founded where?", "answer": "St. John's, Newfoundland -- In 1583, Sir\u00a0Humphrey Gilbert, by the\u00a0royal prerogative\u00a0of\u00a0Queen Elizabeth I, founded\u00a0St. John's.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab3", "question": "What were Donner and Blitzen's names in the 1823 publication of, A Visit from St. Nicholas", "answer": "Dunder and Blixen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f69", "question": "What album track was the first song the Beatles ever performed on their Ed Sullivan Show debut?", "answer": "All My Loving", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592206dfa4edfd43a087adf0", "question": "Tips of hair that are damaged are called what?", "answer": "Split ends", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0c", "question": "In which US state is the Catalina Island located?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c8a74990aac110e4167085", "question": "What province in China does Pu-erh tea originate from?", "answer": "Yunnan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f33", "question": "Whose paintings include \"At the Moulin de la Galette\" and \"At the Moulin Rouge\"?", "answer": "Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90b", "question": "What major river runs through Cleveland?", "answer": "Cuyahoga", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c471", "question": "What computer programming language is often referred to by coders as \"Camel\"?", "answer": "Perl", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad12", "question": "Who was the first Western European Emperor since the collapse of the Western Roman Empire?", "answer": "Charlemagne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc5e", "question": "Football player Pel\u00e9 was born in which Brazilian state?", "answer": "Minas Gerais", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b557", "question": "What flavoured jellybeans were created for United States' President Ronald Reagan's inauguration?", "answer": "Blueberry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a729", "question": "Springfield is the capital of which state?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd9b", "question": "What was first marketed with hillbilly-themed advertising, since its name is an euphemism for moonshine?", "answer": "Mountain Dew", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b92", "question": "How many episodes of \"The Monkees\" were made?", "answer": "58", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d119214fea7fe947a2228b", "question": "Which song from The Beatles' the \"White Album\" was originally entitled \"Maharishi\"?", "answer": "Sexy Sadie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ba", "question": "Which river is often viewed as Russia's national river?", "answer": "Volga", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feccaecec223966ae8f889c", "question": "How many pounds of food does Hollywood superstar Dwayne \"the Rock\" Johnson consume daily?", "answer": "The Rock is well known to consume 10 pounds of food daily and accordingly travels with a 40,000-pound personal gym set!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a67d20565ad31a57c7da", "question": "Who commanded the British Army during most of the American Revolution?", "answer": "General William Howe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb5ab55dad637d903c8818", "question": "What is the world's largest national park?", "answer": "Northeast Greenland National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6662aa5bfecdd737e0866", "question": "How long are the white dashed lines that divide lanes on U.S. roads?", "answer": "10 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a6", "question": "What film duo ends a road trip by driving a Thunderbird off a cliff?", "answer": "Thelma & Louise", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601218b963c99d48cd169af7", "question": "In Swedish, what is \"entrance\" and \"driveway\", respectively?", "answer": "\"Infart\" and \"Uppfart\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e9e", "question": "What movie did the villain Regina Giddens appear in?", "answer": "The Little Foxes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ce", "question": "Where was Enrico Caruso born?", "answer": "Naples, Italy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b426", "question": "What Romanian communist president was executed in December 1989?", "answer": "Nicolae Ceausescu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7e6c9b24f84e0b9f9ffb3", "question": "In computing, what does HTTP stand for?", "answer": "Hypertext Transfer Protocol", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7ce29877e98cb97778a3d", "question": "What U.S city is nicknamed the \"Cradle of Aviation\"?", "answer": "Dayton, Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a238", "question": "What studio album did the band Men at Work release in 1981?", "answer": "Business as Usual", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3f5bff048f679a45ab5d", "question": "What is the chemical term for a peptide; two amino acids linked together?", "answer": "An Amide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff66f4952a821ff76ae8b1e", "question": "In Skamania County, Washington, it\u2019s illegal to kill what creature?", "answer": "Bigfoot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a535", "question": "What is the largest lake found completely within the United States?", "answer": "Lake Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd7d", "question": "Who was the first person to plant a vineyard in the Bible?", "answer": "Noah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388fe", "question": "What musical is set in the fictional English town of Everington?", "answer": "Billy Elliot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b7fbe662d71a5365101a", "question": "Picasso was a suspect in the theft of what famous art piece in 1911?", "answer": "\"Mona Lisa\" by Leonardo da Vinci", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb4", "question": "Each Pac-Man maze features 240 regular dots and how many larger \"power pellets\"?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec26118dc25ca9e12ef645", "question": "London's Trafalgar Square Christmas tree is traditionally given by which country?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60136f3c1381754895396374", "question": "What is the only substance Superman cannot see through?", "answer": "Lead -- Real X-rays cannot penetrate lead, and writers latched onto that fact to keep Supes from being all-powerful.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c9", "question": "The Santa Clara Valley is located in which US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4fa", "question": "What two US state names end with the letter Y?", "answer": "Kentucky and New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c00a", "question": "Strine is the vernacular language spoken in which country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d14", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Spawning\"?", "answer": "Piranha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b919", "question": "What popular snack food was invented in Italy in 610 AD, and was shaped to look like a child's are folded in prayer?", "answer": "A pretzel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8d5532b42d4a3561a9f01", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is the name of the advertising company Francine interviews for and gets mocked at in the elevator?", "answer": "RBK&S", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3cefff048f679a45ab44", "question": "Which animal can cause a tularemia infection in humans while being skinned for cooking purposes?", "answer": "Rabbits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc8", "question": "Pretoria is the capital of which country?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eb0ccf83302ff91e464a0", "question": "What year was the luxury brand \"Tiffany & Co.\" founded?", "answer": "1837", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe1", "question": "At what New York hotel was Sid Vicious accused of killing Nancy Spungen?", "answer": "The Chelsea Hotel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1fe", "question": "What nation was led by the Congress Party from 1947 to 1996 almost uninterrupted?", "answer": "India", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aca4", "question": "Which American inventor held 1,093 patents?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c494", "question": "What is another name for a flower's colorful corolla?", "answer": "Petals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60136f6c1381754895396376", "question": "Where is Superman\u2019s Fortress of Solitude?", "answer": "Arctic Circle -- Although he's had different bachelor pads, he classically heads to the Arctic Circle when he wants to be alone.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5af25aa1b63e5727cf5a4855", "question": "Which song was featured in the 1991 film \"Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves\" and held the number one spot in the UK singles chart for 16 weeks?", "answer": "(Everything I Do) I Do It for You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f31", "question": "Which band member of Alice in Chains died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Layne Staley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3233d5bf195a31e15d739f", "question": "What product changed its original name in the US from the \"Soundabout\"?", "answer": "Sony's Walkman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2bd", "question": "How many seasons were there of the TV show \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "7", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b699263e762b54eb9be9421", "question": "The imperial fluid pint consists of how many imperial fluid ounces?", "answer": "20", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7c", "question": "What beer\u2019s name means \u201clion\u2019s brew\u201d in German?", "answer": "Lowenbrau", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd82212d0de9af39e9d46a8", "question": "Who was the last Roman Emperor?", "answer": "Romulus Augustulus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d4aa2596a59cbdfbd3a6", "question": "What does bone marrow produce?", "answer": "Red and white blood cells, as well as platelets.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b3235b4bf195a31e15d73b2", "question": "What is a system of circulating ocean currents referred to as?", "answer": "A Gyre", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a9b", "question": "On \"Cheers\", what was the name of the upscale seafood restaurant located directly above Cheers?", "answer": "Melville's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f24", "question": "What actor did Michael J. Fox replace as Marty McFly in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "Eric Stolz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac23", "question": "What countries share land borders with Suriname?", "answer": "French Guiana, Guyana, and Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b571", "question": "Who scored the \"Hand of God\" goal?", "answer": "Diego Maradona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb2a265ff7d326b622a76", "question": "What is the fear of mushrooms known as?", "answer": "Mycophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a728cb56bcd28c11938328a", "question": "What is the capital of Delaware?", "answer": "Dover", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad0d", "question": "Which popular Greek philosopher is said to have tutored Alexander the Great?", "answer": "Aristotle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937ebe308d98002fdd633b4", "question": "What is the study of human behaviour and mind called?", "answer": "Psychology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc9", "question": "What can a lycanthrope do ?", "answer": "Change into a wolf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade9", "question": "The first Olympic Games were held in whose honor?", "answer": "Zeus'", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c7", "question": "What disease is carcinomaphobia the fear of?", "answer": "Cancer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76bf3eec85e375820b2cb", "question": "What is the birthplace of denim?", "answer": "Nimes, France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071df63745b36be73039e0", "question": "What is the name of the first Lunar Module to land on the Moon?", "answer": "Eagle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c826", "question": "Nepetalactone is the active ingredient in what pet product?", "answer": "Catnip", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59d1850d3b17032616b590fb", "question": "What 14th century poem contains the earliest reference to Robin Hood?", "answer": "Piers Plowman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133905a", "question": "Painter Salvador Dali was a native of which country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a372", "question": "What is the capital of Iraq?", "answer": "Baghdad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be07", "question": "Frank Sinatra was buried with a bottle of what whiskey?", "answer": "Jack Daniel's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90c", "question": "How many dots are there on a pair of dice?", "answer": "42", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3d0254f032c0db195b497", "question": "What was the Year of the Five Emperors?", "answer": "In 193 AD, there were five claimants for the title of Roman Emperor.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389cb", "question": "What are the six characters in the title of Luigi Pirandello's play i search of?", "answer": "An author", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b155", "question": "What year was Princess Diana born?", "answer": "1961", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac44", "question": "What is a Scimitar?", "answer": "A sword with a curved blade", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fbd", "question": "What Hollywood legend made his screen debut in 1961's \"Splendor in the Grass\"?", "answer": "Warren Beatty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c783", "question": "What two mammals spend their entire lives in the water?", "answer": "Whales and manatees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600cc28d6de0eb824d4052e6", "question": "What is the nickname for the island of Trinidad?", "answer": "Land of the Hummingbird", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ea", "question": "Who is the creator of Perry Mason?", "answer": "Erle Stanley Gardner", "category": "arts"}]